

## +41 77 262 03 29

be.je@gmx.de

in linkedin.com/in/benjamin-jeschke

github.com/bjeschke

## **EDUCATION**

Diploma in Business Informatics FH Würzburg/Schweinfurt 2004-2009 Main focus: E-Commerce und SEO Software Engineering and Development

## SKILLS

## Frontend:

Javascript, Typescript, Angular, Next.js

## **Backend**

PHP, Rust

## **Organisation**

AWS, Gitlab, Guthub, Jira, Shortcut

## **PROFILE**

Detail-oriented front-end developer with 14 years of experience in web development and several years of specialization in Angular and React (TypeScript). Experienced in the AWS environment and back-end development with PHP and Rust. Goal-focused, independent, and structured, yet communicative and committed to teamwork.

# BENJAMIN JESCHKE Senior Frontend Developer

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## Carvolution, Bannwill, Switzerland

Senior Frontend Developer | Sep. 2020 - Dez. 2024

- Implementation and maintenance of scalable Angular components as well as sophisticated services for website, mobile app and internal control system
- Implementing new modules in a headless CMS with PHP to improve performance and flexibility.
- Detail-focused implementation of Figma designs into components.
- Bug fixing and code optimization according to modern standards.

#### Self-employed

Senior Frontend Developer | 2016 - 2020

- Built a Chatbot with Next.js, Langchain and OpenAi
- Implementation of web projects for customers with Wordpress and Javascript
- Implementation of frontend layout according to design templates for VW in React.

#### MHK (Musterhaus Küchen) - Dreieich, DE

Senior Frontend Developer | Mai. 2018 - Okt. 2019

- Building a scalable design system in Javascript with React.js
- Development and maintenance of customer sites with TYPO3 and Bootstrap.
- Creation and optimization of individual WordPress themes.

## Ebbinghaus - Rimpar, DE

Fullstack Software Developer | Jun 2016 - Okt. 2016

- Development and maintenance of Android apps with Xamarin and C#.
- Development of tools and extension of the warehouse system with .NET.

#### Switch Media - Sydney, Australia

Software Engineer | Sep. 2015 - März 2016

- Development of a video-on-demand platform for PlayStation 3 & 4 on behalf of Foxtel Presto using Javascript.
- Implementation of responsive front-end pages for the Parliament of Victoria to manage live video content.
- Full-stack development of tools in the video management system with PHP, JavaScript, HTML and SCSS.

## Multa Medio AG, Würzburg, DE

Frontend Developer | Arp. 2011 - Mär. 2015

- Development of frontend features for German state lottery websites using HTML5, CSS3, Velocity in Eclipse for millions of users.
- Development of interactive elements (tickets, sliders) with JavaScript and jQuery for submitting lottery tickets.
- Creating Java methods to improve backend communication.
- Development of mobile websites and web applications to ensure a consistent user experience across all device types.
- Ensuring UI/UX consistency across all platforms.

#### Eikona - Volkach, DE

Fullstack Developer | Sep. 2010 - Feb. 2011

- Implementation of customer projects (frontend and backend) with CMS.
- Creating WordPress themes.
- Extending a PHP-based CMS with new features.